Guide to the Yasser Alwan Collection AD.MC.002
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
Yasser Alwan Collection
1890-1970
1890-1960
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
Alwan, Yasser, Mr
AD.MC.002
7 paige_boxes - 1,855 prints, 18 photograph albums (containing 541 pages total), 848 slides, 599 negatives
This fascinating collection of vernacular photography presents a great variety of over 3,500 images depicting daily life in Egypt from the decades before the revolution of 1952, from formal studio portraits to amateur family photos of Egyptians, as well as other Arabs, Turks, Armenians, Greeks, Italians and Western expats who lived in or visited Egypt. Yasser Alwan is an independent photographer based in Cairo. His photographs have been exhibited in Cairo, New York, Frankfurt, San Francisco, London, Canterbury and Abu Dhabi. New York University Abu Dhabi hosted a retrospective of his work during the 2011-12 academic year. He taught photography at various institutions including the German University in Cairo
Box 1-7
Biographical / Historical
Yasser Alwan is an independent photographer based in Cairo. His photographs have been exhibited in Cairo, New York, Frankfurt, San Francisco, London, Canterbury and Abu Dhabi. New York University Abu Dhabi hosted a retrospective of his work during the 2011-12 academic year. He is currently teaching photography at the German University in Cairo.
Scope and Contents
The Yasser Alwan collection includes more than 2000 personal, family and studio photographs and offers a varied and often surprising view of the ethnic, cultural and social diversity that characterized Egyptian society in the first half of the twentieth century.
Photographer Yasser Alwan started visiting various flea markets and book merchants in Cairo in the mid-1990s, purchasing old prints and negatives. Most of these date back to the 1920s, 1930s and 1940s, though there are also a significant number from earlier years. The majority of the photographs were sold individually, but there are also groups of photographs discarded together and a small number of albums.
This fascinating collection of vernacular photography presents a great variety of images depicting daily life in Egypt from the decades before the revolution of 1952, from formal studio portraits to amateur family photos of Egyptians, as well as other Arabs, Turks, Armenians, Greeks, Italians and Western expats who lived in or visited Egypt. There are also photographs of trips abroad taken by Egyptians, as well as a collection of postcards dating from the early 20th century through to the 1960s.
Arrangement
The collection has been processed as it was received.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Custodial History
Akkasah, the Center for Photography at NYU Abu Dhabi, acquired the collection in August 2014.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Yasser Alwan, 2006. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.002
Egypt; Studio Photography; Weddings; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Sudan
- Series I: Sudan - Gordon Studio, Undated; 192; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1)
  Sudan
  - Officials walking outside a building with flags, following two soldiers in ceremonial dress. 11.4 x 7.0 cm, Circa 1922-1953; cuid0; 432; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Men; Photographic Prints; Military/Soldiers; Officials; Khartoum, Sudan; Gelatin Silver Prints; Flags; Events/Occasions; Crowds; Uniforms; Medals/Insignia
  - Two men wearing adornments, including feathers in their hair. 7.2 x 11.4 cm, Undated; cuid1; 433; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Photographic Prints; Sudan; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Men; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits
  - Sudanese military officials in three rows. 14.6 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid2; 434; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Fezes/Tarbouches; Fezes/Tarbouches; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Military/Soldiers; Navy; Gelatin Silver Prints; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Sudan; Men; Facial Hair
  - A group portrait of men wearing military uniforms standing in front of an area decorated with crests and streamers. 9.9 x 7.5 cm, 1922-1953; cuid3; 435; Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Sudan; Gelatin Silver Prints; Events/Occasions; Photographic Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Uniforms; Men; Military/Soldiers; Swords/Knives; Fezes/Tarbouches; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Weapons; Medals/Insignia
  - Two men outdoors, one sitting at an easel and drawing, the other standing and looking into the camera. 11.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid4; 436; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Men; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Sudan; Photographic Prints; Carriages/Coaches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - The Saudi Arabian army at Mount Arafat in Mecca. Wide angle photo showing a huge crowd with camels. 8.9 x 6.0 cm, Undated; cuid5; 437; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Arrangement
    with Arabic writing in the back
    Military/Soldiers; Tents; Pilgrims; Men; Animals; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Mecca, Saudi Arabia; Camels; Group Portraits; Boys; Children
  - A Sudanese soldier with facial markings in uniform, standing in front of an archway. 7.3 x 11.9 cm, Undated; cuid6; 438; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Sudan; Gelatin Silver Prints; Turbans; Men; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair
  - Sudanese woodwind and brass band, playing on a field. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid7; 439; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Sudan; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Brass Instruments; Hats; Woodwind Instruments; Uniforms; Musical Instruments; Orchestra; Marching Band
  - A Sudanese soldier with facial markings with a camel and a gun. 6.7 x 10.8 cm, Undated; cuid8; 440; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Individual Portraits; Animals; Guns; Camels; Military/Soldiers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Khartoum, Sudan; Weapons; Buildings; Men
  - A youth wearing traditional dress, carrying two woven baskets on his head. 8.6 x 11.8 cm, Undated; cuid9; 441; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Individual Portraits; Sudan; Photographic Prints; Regional/National Dress; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boys; Children
  - A group of children and women sitting around a tree. 11.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid10; 442; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Boys; Children; Sudan; Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Group Portraits; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Regional/National Dress
  - A procession of the Sudanese cavalry on camels with guns in front of a British officer. 11.8 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid11; 443; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Photographic Prints; Horses; Guns; Men; Flags; Animals; Camels; Sudan; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Weapons; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - Sudanese men with swords on horseback. 11.6 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid12; 444; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Horses; Turbans; Men; Sudan; Regional/National Dress; Photographic Prints; Animals; Swords/Knives; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Weapons; Outdoors
  - A group of tribesmen with shields and spears in a village of thatched houses. 11.1 x 7.1 cm, Undated; cuid13; 445; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Weapons; Armor; Armor; Men; Military/Soldiers; Spears; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Regional/National Dress; Sudan
  - A Sudanese soldier with facial markings on a camel. 7.1 x 11.2 cm, Undated; cuid14; 446; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Animals; Photographic Prints; Turbans; Camels; Men; Sudan; Uniforms; Individual Portraits; Military/Soldiers
  - Sudanese soldiers standing at attention with rifles, a troop in the background hold drums. 11.6 x 6.9 cm, Undated; cuid15; 447; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Fezes/Tarbouches; Men; Military/Soldiers; Fezes/Tarbouches; Weapons; Photographic Prints; Guns; Gelatin Silver Prints; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Sudan; Group Portraits; Musical Instruments
  - A Sudanese man with three camels in the desert. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid16; 448; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Individual Portraits; Hats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Animals; Photographic Prints; Camels; Khartoum, Sudan
  - A steamship on the Nile, with a tugboat named 'panther' beside it. 11.8 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid17; 449; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Boats/Ships; Khartoum, Sudan; Gelatin Silver Prints; Flags; Boats/Ships; Photographic Prints; Nile River
  - The Alexandria Corniche and Saad Zaghloul Square. 11.4 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid18; 450; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Photographic Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Seas; Architecture; Buildings; Carriages/Coaches
  - The Dome, "Al Gubba", Kitchener Medical School (now the medical faculty of the University of Khartoum). 11.4 x 7.0 cm, Undated; cuid19; 451; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Photographic Prints; Architecture; Gelatin Silver Prints; Universities; Khartoum, Sudan; Buildings; Cars/Trucks; Medicine; Transportation; Men; Regional/National Dress
  - Two tribal men, with clay in their hair, made into a horn. 11.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid20; 452; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Jewelry; Sudan; Swords/Knives; Weapons; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Spears; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits
  - An official in a dark uniform with a medal, standing with soldiers with swords and guns (duplicates). 10.0 x 8.2 cm and 13.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid21; 453; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Sudan; Horses; Guns; Swords/Knives; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Medals/Insignia; Men; Weapons; Military/Soldiers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Animals; Fezes/Tarbouches; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A group of Sudanese men, women and children in traditional dress. 11.2 x 6.5 cm, Undated; cuid22; 454; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    with Arabic writing at the back
    Fezes/Tarbouches; Sudan; Photographic Prints; Head Covers/Veils; Hats; Children; Fezes/Tarbouches; Women; Men; Tents; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing
  - Two men with spears and helmets. 8.9 x 11.7 cm, Undated; cuid23; 455; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Regional/National Dress; Weapons; Sudan; Hats; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Spears; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits
  - Pilgrims gathered around the Kaaba in Mecca, Saudi Arabia. 11.0 x 6.7 cm, Undated; cuid24; 456; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Photographic Prints; Mecca, Saudi Arabia; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Pilgrims; The Kaaba/al-kaʿbah (Mecca, Saudi Arabia); Crowds; Men; Women; Head Covers/Veils
  - Sudanese soldiers in uniform standing at attention with bayonets. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid25; 457; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Uniforms; Weapons; Military/Soldiers; Sudan; Photographic Prints; Guns; Gelatin Silver Prints; Flags; Men; Military/Soldiers
  - A military presentation for a British and Sudanese audience, in front of large building (linked ref45). 11.6 x 6.9 cm, Undated; cuid26; 458; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Buildings; Events/Occasions; Ceremonies; Military/Soldiers; Men; Weapons; Photographic Prints; Uniforms; Guns; Military/Soldiers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Swords/Knives; Architecture
  - A man in military uniform on horseback with a sword. 11.1 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid27; 459; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Individual Portraits; Uniforms; Men; Military/Soldiers; Animals; Photographic Prints; Swords/Knives; Horses; Sudan; Military/Soldiers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Turbans; Weapons
  - Sudanese traditional houses. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid28; 460; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Electricity; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Architecture; Sudan; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A Sudanese man carrying animal skin bag. 9.0 x 14.3 cm, Undated; cuid29; 461; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Regional/National Dress; Sudan; Facial Hair
  - Three men grooming a horse, with others looking on. 12.0 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid30; 462; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Sudan; Horses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Animals; Men; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair
  - British - Egyptian ceremony, with flags of the Kingdom of Egypt (1923-1958), and the Pyramids of Giza in the background. Old camera in the mid-ground. 11.6 x 7.3 cm, Undated; cuid31; 463; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Photographic Prints; Ceremonies; Gelatin Silver Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Cairo, Egypt; Egypt; Pyramids; Turbans; Cameras; Flags; Events/Occasions; Audiences/Spectators; Hats; Umbrellas/Parasols; Men; Women
  - An aerial view of a street in Khartoum, Sudan. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid32; 464; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Khartoum, Sudan
  - The Al Kabir Mosque in Khartoum, Sudan. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid33; 465; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Architecture; Carriages/Coaches; Donkeys; Photographic Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Animals; Mosques; Religious Sites
  - A Tabaldi (Baobab) tree outside the walls of a small thatched roof village. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid34; 466; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Sudan; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Architecture; Houses; Outdoors
  - Two mud-brick buildings with domes. 11.2 x 6.8 cm, Undated; cuid35; 467; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Buildings; Streets/Roads; Photographic Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Gelatin Silver Prints; Architecture
  - A military presentation for a British and Sudanese audience, in front of large building (linked ref35). 11.5 x 6.9 cm, Undated; cuid36; 468; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Photographic Prints; Buildings; Uniforms; Architecture; Military/Soldiers; Men; Sudan; Guns; Gelatin Silver Prints; Events/Occasions; Ceremonies; Military/Soldiers; Weapons; Swords/Knives
  - Planes from 47 Squadron of the RAF in front of the Omdurman Bridge. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, 1926-1939; cuid37; 469; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Men; Sudan; Nile River; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Airplanes; Royal Air Force; Bridges; Military/Soldiers; Khartoum, Sudan
  - Planes from 47 Squadron of the RAF and feluccas on the Nile. 10.5 x 6.9 cm, Undated; cuid38; 470; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Airplanes; Boats/Ships; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Royal Air Force; Nile River; Military/Soldiers; Khartoum, Sudan; Sudan
  - A roundabout in front of a military compound. 11.9 x 7.1 cm, Undated; cuid39; 471; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Buildings; Military/Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Motorcycles; Men; Cars/Trucks; Animals; Horses; Military/Soldiers; Sudan; Gelatin Silver Prints; Transportation
  - Wadi Wahesh planes and the Towers of the Three Graces in Sudan. 11.1 x 7.1 cm, Undated; cuid40; 472; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Photographic Prints; Sudan; Gelatin Silver Prints; Oases; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes
  - Four men wearing suits and tarbouches, posing in front of car. 8.3 x 5.9 cm, Undated; cuid41; 473; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Cars/Trucks; Men; Fezes/Tarbouches; Facial Hair; Sudan; Fezes/Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Bags/Purses; Outdoors; Transportation; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A traditional felucca sailing boat on the Nile. 6.5 x 9.4 cm, Undated; cuid42; 475; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    with studio logo at the back
    Photographic Prints; Boats/Ships; Nile River; Sudan; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - A panoramic view of Khartoum. 11.4 x 7.1 cm, Undated; cuid43; 476; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Streets/Roads; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Architecture; Buildings; Photographic Prints
  - A British military ceremony at the Governor General's (Presidential) Palace, Khartoum. 11.7 x 7.1 cm, Undated; cuid44; 477; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Military/Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Ceremonies; Events/Occasions; Architecture; Buildings; Palaces; Government
  - St Matthew's Cathedral (Khartoum Cathedral) on the banks of the Nile.11.3 x 6.7 cm, Undated; cuid45; 478; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Architecture; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Nile River; Photographic Prints; Churches; Religious Sites
  - A car entering the Governor General's (Presidential) Palace in Khartoum, Sudan. 14.1 x 9.3 cm, Undated; cuid46; 479; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Sudan; Architecture; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Cars/Trucks; Palaces; Government; Transportation; Men
  - Four men building wooden wheels. 8.9 x 6.1 cm, Undated; cuid47; 480; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Sudan; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Turbans; Regional/National Dress; Men
  - The Bordein, a paddle steamer built C.1862 by Samuda Brothers of London. 9.1 x 6.2 cm, Undated; cuid48; 481; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Sudan; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Nile River; Boats/Ships; Boats/Ships
  - Train carriages transporting quarried stone. 11.4 x 7.0 cm, Undated; cuid49; 482; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Sudan; Trains; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Transportation
  - A cloudy sky, view from the Omdurman Bridge, Omdurman/Khartoum, Sudan. 11.5 x 7.1 cm, Undated; cuid50; 483; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Architecture; Landscapes; Nile River; Bridges; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Photographic Prints
  - Felucca sail boats on a tributary of the Nile. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid51; 484; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Boats/Ships; Countryside/Rural; Nile River; Sudan; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Rivers
  - The Gordon Hotel, (built 1906). 10.8 x 6.5 cm, Undated; cuid52; 485; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Animals; Architecture; Buildings; Hotels; Khartoum, Sudan; Dogs; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - Six men posing with a car on the side of a road. 8.3 x 5.8 cm, Undated; cuid53; 486; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Fezes/Tarbouches; Sudan; Men; Hats; Uniforms; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cars/Trucks; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Military/Soldiers; Transportation; Facial Hair
  - A tram crossing the Omdurman Bridge, with boats in the foreground. 11.3 x 6.9 cm, Undated; cuid54; 487; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Architecture; Photographic Prints; Sudan; Bridges; Boats/Ships; Khartoum, Sudan; Nile River; Trams; Gelatin Silver Prints; Transportation
  - Al Kabir Mosque - Omdurman's biggest mosque on a cloudy day. 11.4 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid55; 488; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Architecture; Sudan; Photographic Prints; Mosques; Religious Sites
  - Gordon Studio Business card, A. Kazandjian, Khartoum, Sudan. 13.1 x 8.1 cm, Undated; cuid56; 489; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    with a note at the back
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Khartoum, Sudan; Postcards
  - An aerial view of Khartoum, Sudan. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid57; 490; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Architecture; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Khartoum, Sudan
  - Seven men posing with a car and dog (duplicates). 7.9 x 9.9 cm and 11.0 x 7.9 cm, Undated; cuid58; 491; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Cars/Trucks; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Fezes/Tarbouches; Fezes/Tarbouches; Sudan; Photographic Prints; Dogs; Regional/National Dress; Animals; Group Portraits; Lab Coats; Transportation; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A procession of gun mounted military cars in the desert. 12.0 x 7.5 cm, Undated; cuid59; 492; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Guns; Military/Soldiers; Military/Soldiers; Cars/Trucks; Men; Uniforms; Sudan; Weapons; Transportation
  - A troop of soldiers riding camels, one soldier carries a flag. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid60; 493; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Swords/Knives; Guns; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Camels; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Flags; Military/Soldiers; Animals; Weapons; Sudan; Photographic Prints
  - Panorama of Khartoum, Sudan. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; cuid61; 494; Kazandjian, A.; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Architecture; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Streets/Roads; Khartoum, Sudan
  - Holy Virgin Mary Coptic Orthodox Cathedral in Khartoum. 11.0 x 7.0 cm, Undated; cuid62; 495; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Architecture; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Churches; Photographic Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Religious Sites
  - Sudanese traditional boats on the river. 7.2 x 11.0 cm, Undated; cuid63; 2292; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Ports; Boats/Ships; Sudan; Nile River
- Series II: Egypt, 1895-1971; 585 (Box 1-7)
  Egypt
  - Egyptian Family Series, ref1400
    - An Egyptian Family Series - A family of three, Cairo, Egypt. 14.0 x 8.9 cm, 10 May 1928; cuid290; 724; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; French Writing; Cairo, Egypt; Children; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Furnishings
    - An Egyptian Family Series - Three women on the beach. 7.5 x 11.5 cm, 1927; cuid291; 725; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Umbrellas/Parasols; Women; Beaches; Arabic Writing; Seas; Group Portraits